Carmen McRae Collection of Musical Arrangements and Other Materials
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Music, 1931-1976 (Box 1-40)
  - With you, Fran Landesman / Tommy Wolf; Lead sheet (Box-folder 24/32)
  - Without you, Don Newey; Lead sheet (Box-folder 24/33)
  - A woman knows, Charles DeForest; Lead sheet (Box-folder 24/34)
  - Woman talk, Parts (piano, guitar, double bass); Small group #331 (Box-folder 24/35)
  - Wonder why, Sammy Cahn / Nicholas Brodsky; Parts (vocal, trumpet 1-4, trombone 1-4, alto saxophone 1-2, tenor saxophone 1-2, baritone saxophone, piano, guitar, double bass, drums); Arranged by Oliver Nelson; Small group #206 (Box-folder 24/36)
  - Word of warning, Parts (vocal, piano, guitar, double bass, drums, vibes, bells, celeste); Small group #151 (Box-folder 24/37)
  - A world we never knew, Herb Ellis / Leonard Feather; Lead sheet (Box-folder 24/38)
  - Worlds of time, Score; Arranged by Johnny Keating (Box-folder 40/7)
  - Would you believe, Cy Coleman / James Lipton; Lead sheet (Box-folder 24/39)
  - Would you like it, Christine Gardner; Lead sheet (Box-folder 24/40)
  - Ya got me crazy for your love, Tom Peterson / Mike Campbell; Lead sheet (Box-folder 25/1)
  - Yardbird Suite, Charlie Parker; Parts (piano, double bass, drums); Small group #8 (Box-folder 25/2)
  - Yesterday, Score and parts (trumpet 1-3, trombone 1-3, alto saxophone 1-2, tenor saxophone 1-2, baritone saxophone, piano, guitar, double bass, drums); Arranged by Norman Simmons; Small group #341 (Box-folder 37/6)
  - Yesterday I heard the rain, Armando Manzanero / Gene Lees; Piano-vocal score (Box-folder 25/3)
  - Yesterdays, Parts (piano/conductor, guitar, double bass, drums); Arranged by Ralph Burns; Small group #55 (Box-folder 25/4)
  - Yesterday's child, Charles DeForest; Piano-vocal score (Box-folder 25/5)
  - You and I, Parts (piano, double bass) (Box-folder 25/6)
  - You belong to her, Gail Fisher / Oliver Nelson; Lead sheet (Box-folder 25/7)
  - You can be in love, Hamish Menzies; Lead sheet (Box-folder 25/8)
  - You can't go home again, Djalma Ferriera / Leonard Feather; Lead sheet (Box-folder 25/9)
  - You can't go home again, Fran Landesman / Tommy Wolf; Lead sheet (Box-folder 25/10)
  - You can't hide love, Skip Scarborough; Parts (vocal, double bass) (Box-folder 25/11)
  - You don't know what love is, Don Raye / Gene de Paul; Parts (trumpet 1-2, trombone, tenor saxophone, baritone saxophone, piano/conductor, piano, guitar, double bass, drums); Arranged by Bill Holman; Small group #237 (Box-folder 25/12)
  - You don't know what love is, Don Raye / Gene de Paul; Parts (vocal, trumpet 1-4, trombone 1-4, alto saxophone 1-2, tenor saxophone 1-2, baritone saxophone, piano/conductor, double bass, drums); Arranged by Bill Holman (Box-folder 25/12)
  - You go to my head, J. Fred Coots / Haven Gillespie; Parts (piano, double bass); Small group #37 (Box-folder 25/13)
  - You go your way, Tony Scibetta / John Wallowitch; Piano-vocal score (Box-folder 25/14)
  - You have lived in Autumn, Blossom Dearie / Michael Conner; Lead sheet (Box-folder 25/15)
  - You inspire me, Fran Landesman / Tommy Wolf; Lead sheet (Box-folder 25/16)
  - You know who you are, Score and parts (trumpet 1-4, trombone 1-3, alto saxophone 1-2, tenor saxophone 1-3, baritone saxophone, piano/conductor, guitar, double bass, drums); Arranged by Franck Collett (Box-folder 37/7)
  - You know who you are, Parts (vocal, piano, double bass, drums); Arranged by Roger Kellaway (Box-folder 25/17)
  - You leave me breathless, Drum part; Small group #104 (Box-folder 25/18)
  - You look good to me, Sy Lefco / Clement Well Jr.; Lead sheet (Box-folder 25/19)
  - You look like someone, Charles DeForest; Lead sheet (Box-folder 25/20)
  - You or no one, Parts (guitar, drums); Small group #80 (Box-folder 25/21)
  - You perfect stranger, Peter Windsor / Michael Corda; Lead sheet (Box-folder 25/22)
  - You smell so good, Harry Stone / Tommy Wolf; Lead sheet (Box-folder 25/23)
  - You stepped out of a dream, Gus Kahn / Nacio Herb Brown; Piano-vocal score (Box-folder 25/24)
  - You swing, baby see Brubeck folder, Dave Brubeck; Lyric sheet
  - You taught me everything I know, Johnny Rotella / Mitchell Tableporter; Lead sheet (Box-folder 25/25)
  - You tell yourself, Dave Grusin / Arthur Hamilton; Lead sheet (Box-folder 25/26)
  - You took advantage of me, Parts (piano, double bass); Small group #6 (Box-folder 25/27)
  - You were sent to me, Carmen Clarke / Bill Tenayson; Lead sheet (Box-folder 25/28)
  - You'll see (a lethal love song), Carroll Coates; Lyric and lead sheet (Box-folder 25/29)
  - Your face is familiar, Bob Comstock / Gene DiNovi; Lead sheet (Box-folder 25/30)
  - Your love, Parts (piano, double bass, drums); Small group #405 (Box-folder 25/31)
  - You're a joy, Bernie Hanighen / Tadd Dameron; Piano-vocal score (Box-folder 25/32)
  - You're a mystery, Sergio Mihanovich; Lead sheet (Box-folder 25/33)
  - You're all I need, Parts (piano, double bass, drums) (Box-folder 25/34)
  - You're beginning to be a habit with me, Harry Warren / Al Dubin; Lead sheet (Box-folder 25/35)
  - You're crying, Quincy Jones / Leonard Feather; Lead sheet (Box-folder 25/36)
  - You're everything, Score and parts (trumpet 1-4, trombone 1-4, flute 1-3, clarinet 1-2, piano, guitar, double bass, drums); Arranged by Thad Jones (Box-folder 37/8)
  - You're everything, Parts (vocal, piano, double bass, drums) (Box-folder 25/37)
  - You're lookin' at me, Bobby Troup; Lead sheet (Box-folder 25/38)
  - You're mine, Parts (flute, clarinet, English horn, piano, double bass, drums); Small group #129 (Box-folder 25/39)
  - You're my everything, Parts (vocal, trumpet 1-2, trombone, tenor saxophone, baritone saxophone, piano/conductor, double bass, drums); Arranged by Bill Holman (Box-folder 25/40)
  - You're so bad for me, Fran Landesman / Tommy Wolf; Lead sheet (Box-folder 25/41)
  - You're the only friend I have, E. Pease / M. Scarpiello / H. Payne; Lyric sheet (Box-folder 25/42)
- Miscellany, 1961-1993 (Box 41)
  Includes correspondence, photographs, song lists, program notes, and promotional materials.
  - Artwork, undated, Butterfly wing art on paper (3 items) (Box-folder 41/1)
  - Clipping, September 1961, Jazz Day magazine (Box-folder 41/2)
  - Correspondence, 1964-1993, undated (Box-folder 41/3)
  - Honors, 1974, 1989, Certificates (2); The Smithsonian Institution; State of New Jersey (Box-folder 41/4)
  - Photographs, undated, Carmen and friends at Chez Gaby, Club Tagada, Paris; Jack Leonard (signed); Louis Armstrong walking with trumpet (photo by Maynard Frank Wolfe) (Box-folder 41/5)
  - Printed materials, 1979, undated, Benny Carter and Carmen McRae Japanese tour souvenir book; Dave Brubeck Anthology, Vol. 1 (featuring photographs and writings regarding McRae) (Box-folder 41/6)
  - Set lists, 1984, undated (Box-folder 41/7)